THE HUSBAND
THIS SERIES IS FICTITIOUS
CHILDREN WERE FILMED SAFELY
GEN AI WAS USED IN SELECT SCENES
[Seonja] How did he get you?
I was sleeping at home,
and he was standing right there
when I opened my eyes.
[Seonja] So maybe, do you think
you might have wronged someone?
Maybe you hurt someone.
The kidnapper called my husband
and told him I was kidnapped,
but he just said, "Do whatever
you want with her" and hung up.
When you get out of here,
can you let the police know
that Lee Seonja from Songmu-dong
died in this place?
[whimpers]
[gasps]
Over here!
Help me! Please!
Wait a second! Help me! Please!
[panting]
-Oh my gosh!
-Please help me.
What's going on?
[exhales] You must've been terrified.
Let me take you to the hospital first.
No, don't.
Please go to the police station.
I have to report him first.
You can use this.
Ah! I'm so sorry.
No, it's fine.
JANG DOSIK
SEONGJIN POLICE STATION
Honey.
[screams] Honey!
No!
[shrieking]
Honey!
Honey, are you okay?
-Are you okay?
-[shrieks]
Go after them already.
I said, are you okay?
Noh Manhui!
Chase them down and kill them!
[panting] Seyun.
STYLE
::cue()
Seyun!
Seyun.
Seyun, come on.
Seyun. Come on. Please.
Seyun, can you hear me?
Hey, are you okay?
Let's go. Come on, Seyun.
Look out!
You bastard.
Seyun.
[groans]
Honey.
[Seyun screams]
[shouts]
[both panting, groaning]
Let's end this here.
Mr. Kang.
-[shouts]
-[muffled screaming]
You messed
with the wrong person.
Die, both of you!
-[gunshot]
-Hands up! Police! Don't move!
[Taeju gasping]
[Dosik] Put down your weapon!
-Get him!
-Yes, sir!
Move!
-[Dosik] Go after him!
-[Hyeonsu] Stop right there!
[Detective Oh] Stop, Noh Manhui!
-Stop right there!
-Get moving!
Don't let him get away!
-[officer 1] Stop, Noh Manhui!
-[officer 2] Stop, you punk!
-Arrest him.
-[Hyeonsu] Yes, sir.
Mr. Kang Taeju.
Get up.
-[Oh] Stop right there, Noh Manhui!
-[officer 2] I said stop!
[officer 3] Go after him!
Noh Manhui!
[Hyeonsu] Mr. Kang, for solicitation
of kidnapping and murder,
-theft and impersonating a public--
-Seyun!
[Hyeonsu] Don't move!
You have the right to remain silent,
and you have the right to an attorney.
-If you can't afford one…
-Seyun!
…one will be provided for you.
-She's injured! Call an ambulance!
-[Hyeonsu] Yes, sir!
Seyun!
[Detective Oh] Damn it!
Move!
Noh Manhui!
Hey!
Stop right there, punk!
-Stop!
-[officer] Careful.
[Detective Oh] Hey, Noh Manhui!
Stop!
-Go that way!
-[Detective Oh] That prick.
STYLE
::cue()
That way. You two, that way.
-Yes, sir.
-Move it! This way.
[officer] Hey, to the left…
Don't move!
[groaning]
[panting]
I have to go, okay?
I have to go!
We have to get out of…
Oh, gosh, Gyeongae.
[groans]
-What happened? Tell me.
-[Manhui] Are you okay?
I said, are you okay?
You can't even handle a…
[whimpering] Hold on.
Don't touch me.
-Let's get you to the hospital.
-I can't move right now! Don't touch me.
Oh, no.
You have to leave me.
I'm not going anywhere alone!
Noh Manhui.
-Huh?
-Don't get caught, okay?
Just come back for me. You got that?
Okay, babe? Babe.
You have to come back for me.
You got that?
Go, already! Go on.
I said go already! I swear to God…
[Manhui] I'll be right back.
I'll be back to get you.
-Okay?
-[Gyeongae] Okay.
Just go!
Don't you dare get caught!
Get out of here!
Hurry!
[engine starts]
[tires squealing]
BABY ON BOARD
61K 9024
[officer] It seems…
We're searching the house first.
Search the place.
THE HUSBAND
STYLE
::cue()
Hey, help them tape off the area.
[officer] Yes, sir.
[police radio chatter]
EMERGENCY SERVICES, AMBULANCE
Luckily, it looks like the impact
missed the vital organs.
-Still, we should get him checked out.
-Got it.
Well…
Detective, what's going on with my wife?
Is she okay?
You don't get to ask about her.
Is she conscious?
Mr. Kang. You're under arrest right now.
Hey, don't move. It's okay.
Where…
Where am I?
In an ambulance.
Don't you remember what happened at all?
[Dosik] Ms. Ko Seyun.
How are you feeling?
Oh, I'm Detective Jang Dosik.
Captain of Major Crimes at Seongjin PD.
Police…
Where's my husband?
What happened to my husband?
Oh, don't worry about him.
He's been arrested.
Arrested? Why?
If you could just calm down,
we'll tell you everything in due--
No. Where is he?
I have to see him right now.
Honey!
Seyun.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
That's good.
What… Why… But why are you…
Why are you in handcuffs?
Why…
You didn't do anything wrong.
He's suspected of soliciting
your kidnapping and murder.
It's not him you want.
What do you mean?
The real culprits were a married couple.
A couple?
Yes, the guy abducted me,
and the woman pretended
to be another victim in the next room.
They're absolutely insane.
I'm telling you,
he's here to save my life!
Okay, we'll take note.
We'll look into that
as part of our investigation.
Mr. Kang, let's go.
Wait, but…
Let's go.
-[radio chirps]
-[Detective Oh] Captain.
We've lost the suspect.
One of our officers was
attacked during the pursuit.
-Choi.
-Yes, sir.
[Dosik] Set up checkpoints
within a 10-kilometer radius
and call in neighboring precincts.
Copy that.
[Detective Oh] Also, we've located
a female inside the suspect's residence.
Her lower-body pain
is too severe to transport her.
STYLE
::cue()
EMERGENCY SERVICES, AMBULANCE
[Dosik] Is it serious?
Mr. Kang, this way.
How's she looking?
She has paralysis below the waist
and is in severe pain.
She strongly resists
any attempt to examine her,
so we can't check her vitals
or perform basic first aid.
It'd be best to have a doctor's evaluation
before we transport her.
Try moving your leg.
Can you not move it?
What about your back?
[screaming]
It hurts.
Doctor.
We found these meds on the desk.
PRESCRIPTION, KIM GYEONGAE
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
RELIEVES NERVE PAIN
FROM SPINAL NERVE COMPRESSION
Help me.
So, how's she looking?
She has a pre-existing spinal condition.
It looks like the trauma caused
acute hemorrhaging at the lesion site.
Based on her pain response,
the bleeding and swelling
will likely worsen
the spinal cord compression.
I… I don't really…
The pressure on her spinal cord
is causing the tissue to die.
If she doesn't get surgery right now,
her legs will be permanently paralyzed.
If it gets any worse, she may even die.
Help me, please.
SYSTEM STATUS
ADMIN SETTINGS
DELETE ALL DATA
DATA WIPE IN PROGRESS…
CLOUD DRIVE, LOCAL SERVER (HOME),
BACKUP SERVER (SCHOOL)
TOTAL DATA WIPE IN PROGRESS
DELETION COMPLETE
STYLE
::cue()
[siren wailing]
POLICE CHECKPOINT
This is Checkpoint Three.
Nothing to report.
[whistle blows]
Have a good day.
[siren wailing]
-Remove them quickly!
-[whistle blowing]
BABY ON BOARD
61K 9024
[officer]
Detective Oh, I think you should see this!
What is it?
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD
What's this guy's deal?
Oh, you have got to be kidding me.
[siren wailing]
-[siren stops]
-[phone buzzes]
What did you find?
Hey, Captain, we've recovered
several damaged IDs at the scene.
We also found a bloodstained
sledgehammer, knives, and a saw,
which appear to be murder weapons.
We'll need to investigate these.
[Dosik]
Secure the scene and the evidence.
Get Forensics out there immediately.
Yeah. Tell them it's urgent.
-Hey, Choi.
-Yes, sir. This way.
[breathing heavily]
STYLE
::cue()
Seyun!
Seyun, my baby…
Are you okay, sweetie?
I'm fine, Dad.
Oh, look at you, you poor thing.
How's she looking?
Yes, sir. She has multiple contusions
and abrasions throughout,
but fortunately, there are
no signs of serious injury.
She's severely dehydrated
and malnourished,
-so we've started her on IV fluids.
-I see.
You'll be fine, my dear.
Okay.
Hey, Seyun. You all right?
Chiung.
[sighs] Do you have any idea
how worried I was?
This is all so crazy.
I'm so relieved.
Thank goodness you're all right.
-Dr. Ko.
-Yes?
May I speak to you for a minute?
What is it?
Kang Taeju is in the hospital right now.
What did you say?
He's with the cops.
Apparently, they're with the person
who kidnapped Ms. Ko.
What?
Are you saying those criminals
are at the hospital right now?
They're saying Dr. Kang
actually rescued Ms. Ko.
What…
So he had her kidnapped
and then rescued her?
What on earth are you talking about?
Something feels off.
It's as if the cops
actually believe Dr. Kang.
Where are they right now?
Captain, are you sure about this?
Shouldn't we take them
straight to the station?
Run her info.
See if she's gotten a scan
at this hospital before.
[typing]
PATIENT INFORMATION
NAME: KIM GYEONGAE
[doctor] Yes, we've got her MRI
from six months ago.
[Dr. Ko] What are you doing here?
What do you think you are doing?
What are these criminals
doing at my hospital?
Dr. Ko, if you could please calm down…
How am I supposed to calm down right now?
Please don't get the wrong idea.
Mr. Kang is still under arrest.
But she's in such critical condition that…
Critical?
[scoffs]
Be that as it may,
these people are criminals
that did horrible things to my daughter.
How could I let them in my hospital?
That is just ridiculous!
You, say something.
Have you forgotten what you've done?
You orchestrated the hit on my daughter,
you broke into my home with a gun
and took three billion won from me.
You really think you have
any right to be in this room?
Well, I took the money for a reason.
What are you even saying?
I couldn't tell you at the time,
but I needed it as bait
to lure out the culprit.
What? A bait?
Yes, I was planning to give it back
as soon as I got Seyun back.
STYLE
::cue()
Detective. Is this true?
Is he telling the truth?
We can't be sure yet,
but a lot of Ms. Ko's statements
align with what Dr. Kang is saying.
But we'll have to investigate further.
Okay, fine.
Let's say you're telling the truth.
Then where's my three billion?
Let me see it now!
I put it in my trunk.
What?
I put it in the trunk
of the car I was driving.
-Check the trunk.
-[Hyeonsu] Yes, sir.
Wait, you believe
what this bastard is saying?
Well, I don't,
so get him out of here!
And that criminal too.
She's developed an expanding hematoma
due to acute hemorrhage within the tumor.
If we don't take action,
it'll completely compress her spinal cord.
If she doesn't get surgery right now,
she's not going to survive this, sir.
[scoffs]
So,
you're asking to have her
operated on at our hospital?
That criminal?
We have to find out
who kidnapped Seyun and why.
If she dies, we'll never
get to the truth, Father.
No way.
[Dosik] Dr. Ko.
I understand this situation
may be quite upsetting for you,
but he does have a point.
What on earth are you trying to say?
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm the director of this hospital!
Plus, do you think anyone
would take on this surgery?
No doctor here would be up for it!
I'm doing this surgery.
What?
Why on earth are you doing this?
What are you plotting?
If you think I have ulterior motives,
you can watch over me as I operate.
I don't mind.
[scoffs]
Have you lost your damn mind?
No way!
Get him out of here!
And get that woman out of here too!
Please let him do it.
Seyun.
Dad.
Let Taeju operate on her.
[Dr. Ko] Seyun, that woman is a criminal.
Not just any criminal.
She's the one who kidnapped you.
I know,
but I want to know why they did this
and why they kidnapped me.
I want to know the truth.
[line ringing]
Why won't this prick pick up?
Come on, damn it.
[beeps]
STYLE
::cue()
[knocking on door]
This space is for doctors
and patients only.
Please wait outside for a moment.
He's in handcuffs, isn't he?
I'll take full responsibility.
Okay. I understand.
Give us the room.
I'll handle the rest.
Yes, sir.
[door opens]
[door closes]
You belong behind bars, not in an OR.
Is it a criminal-to-criminal thing?
Or are you taking care of your accomplice?
Why on earth did I ever
accept you into my family?
I know.
Why did you?
I'm wondering the same thing myself.
How are you going to do this surgery?
I'm going to do it by the book.
"By the book"?
Sure, you should, as a doctor.
But not all life is of equal value.
That woman is not a patient.
She put your wife in danger
and tried to take her life.
[sighs]
The OR is a strange place.
Even if you prepare
for every possible scenario,
you still run into unexpected situations.
But that's not the doctor's fault, is it?
-Take off his cuffs.
-Yes, sir.
[Dosik]
This is only until the surgery's over.
I'll be watching,
so don't do anything stupid.
Don't forget you're still a suspect.
[Taeju] Understood.
STYLE
::cue()
-[exhales heavily]
-Captain, are you sure about this?
What if something goes wrong?
Let's see how it goes.
Yes, sir.
What are you… What the hell are you doing?
Sir, what are you doing?
Please! Please don't do that!
Please pull her up! Please, sir!
Watch your precious daughter die!
-[Dr. Ko] Seyun!
-[Seyun's mother] Seyun!
-[Dr. Ko] No!
-Honey!
[Manhui] Just because you're rich,
you think you can mock me?
[choking]
[Manhui] You're sorry?
Well, sorry's not going to cut it.
You bastard!
I'm going to kill you!
I'm… I'm going to…
I'm going to find you
and tear you to pieces, you bastard!
I'll operate on you.
Don't worry, I'm a doctor.
It's my job and duty to save lives.
-[monitor beeping]
-[breathing shakily]
[Taeju] But…
After what you did to my wife…
When I think about that…
Maybe you're not worth saving.
Ready to start anesthesia.
STYLE
::cue()
The MRI shows that the bleeding
occurred quite a while ago,
resulting in an extensive hematoma.
We'll remove the hematoma first,
and then proceed with hemostasis.
Anesthesia, any issues?
All clear. Vitals are stable.
Let's get started.
Ten blade.
Exposing the field. Retractor.
Starting the laminectomy. Drill.
[drill whirring]
I see a subdural hematoma
caused by tumor hemorrhage.
There is severe spinal cord compression.
I’m going to make the dural incision.
Eleven blade.
Suction.
Forceps.
The hematoma's mostly cleared.
Let's double-check it
then re-check the bleeding site.
There's active bleeding at the tumor base.
Bipolar.
Turn the bipolar down, please.
[nurse 1] Turning the bipolar down.
[Dr. Ko] The OR is a strange place.
Even if you prepare
for every possible scenario,
you still run into unexpected situations.
But that's not the doctor's fault, is it?
[alarm beeping]
[doctor] Dr. Kang!
Dr. Kang!
Dr. Kang, are you okay?
D-Dr. Kang?
[nurse 1] Gelatin sponge, please.
SPONGE USED TO STOP BLEEDING
[doctor] Give me the whole thing.
[nurse 1] We need more gelatin sponge.
[nurse 2] Gelatin sponge coming up.
STYLE
::cue()
[doctor] Dr. Kang,
we still have bleeding. Dr. Kang!
We need more gauze.
-STAT!
-[nurse 2] I got it.
I got more gauze.
Why isn't he getting
the bleeding under control?
What's going on in there?
[doctor] Anesthesia, are vitals stable?
[anesthesiologist]
Heart rate is climbing. We're at 140.
Gauze, please.
[doctor] The bleeding isn't stopping!
-[anesthesiologist] Transfusion, please.
-[nurse 2] On it.
[anesthesiologist]
BP is still tanking. We're at 60 over 30!
[doctor] Dr. Kang!
[Dr. Im] What just happened?
-[doctor] More gauze, please.
-[nurse 2] Got it.
[doctor] The bleeding's slowing.
[Taeju] Suction.
[doctor] Anesthesia, how are the vitals?
[anesthesiologist] They're still unstable.
[doctor] We need more blood.
[nurse 2] I'll request more units
from the blood bank.
The immediate crisis is over,
and her vitals are steady for now.
[Dr. Ko] Good job.
Well done,
saving that woman.
Mr. Kang.
The bag of money you mentioned…
It wasn't in the trunk.
What are you talking about?
I definitely put it in the trunk.
[scoffs]
I knew it.
You were planning to return the money?
[scoffs]
You're putting on an act after hiding
that money somewhere, aren't you?
No, that's not it, Father. I swear.
[Dr. Ko] Stop it.
I am absolutely disgusted.
I'm going down to the station
to formally press charges
against him tomorrow.
You see who he truly is now?
Let's go.
Get up. Come on.
Dr. Ha. A moment.
[Dosik] Let's go down to the station.
-Cuff him.
-Yes, sir.
STYLE
::cue()
SEONGJIN POLICE STATION
SAFE SEONGJIN, TRUSTED POLICE
[Dosik] Okay, let's go over this again.
You met Lee Suhyeong
while you were being interrogated
about your wife's abduction,
and you fled to meet him?
-Yes.
-I don't quite understand.
Why did you run?
Mr. Lee told me that he'd help me
find out where my wife was.
He said the guy did
the same thing to his wife.
I mean…
Sure, he said he knew
your wife's whereabouts,
but how could you trust
a total stranger so easily?
He was different.
He wasn't like you people.
At least he knew I wasn't behind this.
And that's why you did as he said?
I had no choice. I had to save my wife.
You had no choice, huh?
[scoffs]
You ran from a police investigation,
infiltrated the NFS with a fake ID,
robbed your own in-laws, opened fire,
and attempted murder.
And you nearly got Detective Park killed.
You expect me to believe
you did all this to save your wife?
That's exactly what a man
who wants to save his wife would do.
I told you from the beginning
that it wasn't me.
That I don't even know who he is.
And what did you do?
Did any of you actually listen?
No. You just pegged me as an accomplice.
My wife could've died
while you were wasting time.
So put yourselves in my shoes.
What would you have done?
As for me,
I had to do whatever it took to save her.
You sent this, right?
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD
NOH MANHUI
Yeah.
Why did you send it?
Because I found the real perp.
Wasn't that a calculated move
to build yourself an alibi?
[sighs] Honestly,
I still don't know what to believe.
Whether you were actually
trying to save your wife,
or you just ended up saving her
when things went sideways.
Fine.
Let's say you're telling the truth.
But what about the money?
Where is that three billion?
I told you. I left it in the trunk.
STYLE
::cue()
We searched the whole thing
but found nothing.
So be honest with us, Mr. Kang.
Nothing's changed, has it?
Let's just drop it.
You have no intention
of believing a word I say anyway.
Once your arrest warrant is issued,
you'll be locked up for a while.
You should probably get used to this.
CHICKEN & BEER
Ugh, what the hell?
Hey, can you move your car so I can go?
[reporter] Authorities have confirmed
that one of the primary suspects
in the recent hospital
kidnapping case remains at large.
-What the hell is wrong with this guy?
-Police have issued a nationwide APB
for 42-year-old Noh Manhui
and are tracking him.
[horn honking]
Hey. I said, move your car.
Geez, do you not hear me? Move it already!
[Manhui] Okay, I will.
Are you kidding me right now?
I should just kill that prick. Seriously…
Couldn't he just do it
when I asked the first time?
Why did he have to piss me off?
I should just--
[gurgling]
You should've just left.
I said I'd move it.
Can't you hear me?
I said, can't you hear me?
Answer me, you prick.
STYLE
::cue()
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
STAIRWELL
FIRE DOOR, KEEP CLOSED
DO NOT PLACE OBJECTS
NEAR FIRE DOOR
Hello? Yes, Doctor.
Yes, I'll come to you.
WING 102 ROOM 07
KIM G.A
[monitor beeping]
POTASSIUM CHLORIDE
STYLE
::cue()
Dr. Kang!
What are you doing right now?
Potassium chloride?
Giving undiluted IV potassium chloride
would cause hyperkalemia
and cardiac arrest.
You're a doctor, so surely you knew that.
Dr. Ha Jeongsoo.
I knew all along that she was a patient
at our hospital and that you were
her attending physician.
Why would this woman,
who was your patient…
kidnap my wife?
And why are you trying
to kill this woman now?
That's…
The Dr. Ha I know
would never do anything like this.
Who is it?
Who's calling the shots?
Is it Director Ko Dongchan?
It's him, right?
THE HUSBAND
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[Dr. Ko] The entire future of
this hospital is riding on this project.
[Taeju] What's going on here?
[Dr. Ko] What if
the whole world finds out?
Seyun will have to shoulder all of that.
[Dosik] We don't know what else
we'll find, so search every inch.
[Detective Oh] What the hell is this?
[granddaughter]
Where's my grandma? Where is she?
[Jeongsoo]
I honestly don't know anything.
I was only doing what I was told.
[Dr. Im] That was Dr. Ha, wasn't it?
Taeju?
[Taeju] You and Kim Gyeongae.
What is the connection between you two?
[Dr. Ko] If you want to know so badly,
ask that woman once she wakes up.
Translated by Hyun Sik Yoon